# IASMINI VOLTOLINI CORSO

Porto - Portugal • +351 934 039 340 • iasminivoltolini@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/iasmini-voltolini-corso

### Math teacher venturing into the IT world

#### Summary

As I currently have some free time, I decided to expand my area of expertise and improve myself in subjects that arouse my interest.

I opted for the IT area (Information Technology), in which I had a brief contact during my graduation. I started watching some basic HTML, CSS and JavaScript courses, and became even more interested. Among the research I did, I found the Python programming language, which coincidentally was created by a mathematician, the Dutchman Guido van Rossum. I felt very comfortable already in my first contacts with the language, so I am investing my time and focusing on Python. I am very motivated, and I hope that soon I will be able to find a professional opportunity to put into practice the knowledge I have been acquiring.

#### Work experience

Feb 2018 - Jan 2021

Financial assistant

Etil Etiquetas

Activities I performed:

- Receiving orders;
- Issuing invoices;
- Quality control;
- Banking services;
- Purchase of raw material;
- Order delivery with the company's vehicle.

The company operates in the printing business, producing labels for clothing and diffrent kinds of adhesive labels.

The company has a large amount of work orders from several clients, but the number of employees was small. Since I was the oldest employee in the office, I was responsible for the most important tasks. I was in charge of receiving the order, which was mostly done by phone or e-mail. After registration, the order was forwarded to the production sector that made the labels. In the meantime, I was responsible for writing the invoice referring to the order. At the end of production, it was necessary to perform quality control, checking whether the items were in accordance with the order. At this same moment, the items were separated by type, color and size. After being packed, they were left to await delivery, which usually took place twice a day. During the deliveries that I made, it was very common to make bank services such as: payments, deposits and receipts; when necessary I went to the suppliers to make the purchase of raw materials.

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

Math teacher

Santa Catarina State Government

During this period, I worked as a substitute teacher in several schools, in different cities in the region where I lived. I worked in the kindergarten, performing all the tasks and care that involve children from 0 to 4 years old. I also taught the subject of mathematics, for which I have a degree. I gave classes to students in elementary school (2nd and 3rd cycle) and high school. In some moments, due to the school's needs, I taught the subject of Physics.

Among the activities I performed were:

- Preparation of classes;
- Preparation and correction of assessments;
- Extra-curricular activities (presentations, fairs and other events);
- Tutoring;
- Private classes.

Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

Office assistance

Escritório Contábil Timbó Ltda - ESCOTIL

During this period that I worked as an assistant in an accounting office, I was able to acquire experience related to taxes, tributes, legislation, and payroll details.

Besides the internal activities, I performed external services. Among the main ones were the banking services such as payments and receipts of accounting fees; the delivery and collection of mailbags for several companies; I was also in charge of organizing and filing the companies' documents (arquive file). All the external services were performed with the company's vehicle.

## Education

2021 - 2021

Língua Italiana e Literaturas de Língua Italiana

Boscolo Scuola d'italiano

During this pandemic period I decided to put into practice some of the items that were on my list of personal goals, and one of them was to take an Italian language course. Therefore, I chose to dedicate some time in my day to achieve this goal.

2018 - 2019

General English Course

KNN Idiomas - Brazil

ESL - English as a Second Language

2011 - 2017

Mathematics Degree

Regional University of Blumenau (FURB)

During my graduation period, I had the opportunity to participate in several fairs and symposia about mathematics and teaching techniques. I also had the change to take part in the PIBID (Institutional Teaching Initiation Scholarship Program) which is an initiative that aims to improve and valorize the formation of teachers for basic education. In which I had the experience of teaching mathematics in the public school system, besides helping teachers and applying different learning methods.